https://monition.com/gdpr-privacy-cookies-policy/

GDPR PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY
What is the purpose of this document?RS Components is a "data controller". This means that we are responsible for deciding how we hold and use personal information about you. This privacy notice makes you aware of how and why your personal data will be used and how long it will usually be retained for. Our full policy details, which are in addition to the details in this Privacy Notice, are set out in the RS Components Privacy Policy, a copy of which can be found at:https://uk.rs-online.comIt provides you with certain information that must be provided under the General Data Protection Regulation ((EU) 2016/679) (GDPR).
Data Protection PrinciplesWe will comply with data protection law and principles, which means that your data will be:• Used lawfully, fairly and in a transparent way.• Collected only for valid purposes that we have clearly explained to you and not used in any way that is incompatible with those purposes.• Relevant to the purposes we have told you about and limited only to those purposes.• Accurate and kept up to date.• Kept only as long as necessary for the purposes we have told you about.• Kept securely.
The Kind Of Information We Hold About YouIn connection with your enquiry about our products and/ or services, or enquiry about an existing order or an enquiry about any employment vacancies, we will collect, store, and use the following categories of personal information about you:• The information you have provided to us in connection with your enquiry or in relation to your order or in your curriculum vitae and covering letter.• The information you have provided for the order or enquiry, or on our online ‘contact us’ form, including name, title, delivery address, billing address, payment information, telephone number, personal email address, date of birth, gender, employment history, qualifications.• Any information you provide to us during the order, enquiry or recruitment process.
How Is Your Personal Information Collected?We collect personal information from the following sources:• You.• Automated technologies, such as cookies on our website.• Third parties, such as from providers of technical, payment and delivery services, recruitment agencies and referees.• From publicly available sources within the EU such as, Google Adwords.
How We Will Use Information About YouWe will use the personal information we collect about you:• To reply to your enquiry.• To supply products and/or services to you.• In a way in which is in our legitimate interest (or those of a third party).• Comply with legal or regulatory requirements.• Full details of our lawful basis for processing your information and details of our legitimate interests can be found in the RS Components Privacy Policy, a copy of which can be found at https://uk.rs-online.com
If You Fail to Provide Personal InformationWhere we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel your order for a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time. We will also not be able to process any employment application or enquiry.Automated Decision-MakingYou will not be subject to decisions that will have a significant impact on you based solely on automated decision-making.Data sharingWhy might you share my personal information with third parties?We will only share your personal information to specific internal third parties, external third parties and our professional advisers, unless required by law. Full details of disclosures of your personal data can be found in the RS Components Privacy Policy, a copy of which can be found athttps://uk.rs-online.comAll third parties are required to take appropriate security measures to protect your personal information in line with our policies. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes. We only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.Data SecurityWe have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal information to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need-to-know. They will only process your personal information on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. Full details of disclosures of our data security can be found in the RS Components Privacy Policy, a copy of which can be found at https://uk.rs-online.comWe have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected data security breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected breach where we are legally required to do so.Data RetentionHow Long Will You Use My Information For?We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for seven years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.Rights Of Access, Correction, Erasure, And RestrictionYour Rights In Connection With Personal InformationUnder certain circumstances, by law you have the right to:• Request access to your personal information (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.• Request correction of the personal information that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold about you corrected.• Request erasure of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it.• You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).• Object to processing of your personal information where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground.• You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes.• Request the restriction of processing of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of personal information about you, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.• Request the transfer of your personal information to another party.If you want to review, verify, correct or request erasure of your personal information, object to the processing of your personal data, or request that we transfer a copy of your personal information to another party, please contact us at any time at RS Components at Bondhay Complex, Whitwell Common, Worksop S80 3EH or +44 (0)1909 722000 or administration@monition.com.Right To Withdraw ConsentWhen you first provided us with your personal data, you provided consent to us processing your personal information. You have the right to withdraw your consent for processing at any time. To withdraw your consent, please contact RS Components at Bondhay Complex, Whitwell Common, Worksop S80 3EH or 01909 722000 or administration@monition.com. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent. Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will, subject to our retention policy, dispose of your personal data securely.Contact UsQuestions, comments and requests regarding this privacy notice are welcomed, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, and should be addressed to.You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues.I acknowledge that I have read a copy of Monition Limited's Privacy Notice and that I understood it and consent to the processing of my data in accordance with the terms of the RS Components Privacy Policy.
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish. Accept Reject Read MorePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Necessary
Always Enabled
